Quirini, Helen; Papers apap102
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- General Electric, 1918-2007; Undated; 5; 6.88 cubic ft.
  - Fast for New York's Working Poor, 2000; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 3)
  - Frankly Speaking, 2009 September 24 (Dvd 18)
  - Frankly Speaking, GE Pension, 2000 April 10 (Video-tape 70)
  - Gail George, Bennington Center, 1998 August 22 (Dvd 19)
  - Gail George Talks, Undated (Dvd 20)
  - Gail George Talks about Communicating through Performance Art, Undated (Video-tape 71)
  - GEAA, 1943-1945; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 4)
  - GE Annual Meeting, Picketing, Schenectady, 2005 April 27 (Video-tape 72)
  - GE Annual Meeting, Plantgate-Demo, 1999 April 21 (Video-tape 73)
  - GE Annual Meeting, Rally, 2003 April (Video-tape 74)
  - GE Annual Report, 2003 (Cd 10)
  - GE Apprentice Alumni Association, 1951-1959; 1963-1965; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 5)
  - GE Apprentice Alumni Association, 1969-1987 (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 6)
  - GE Apprentice Alumni Posters for Dinner Dance, 1943; 1951 (Oversized 1, Folder 12)
  - GE Benefits Seminar, 1991 November 13-1991 November 15 (Video-tape 76)
  - GE Contract, 2000 (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 7)
  - GE Corporate Annual Meeting, Independent Board Chairman Proposals and Related Materials, 1997; 1999; 2002-2009; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 8)
  - GE Demonstration, 1995 June 15 (Video-tape 75)
  - GE During World War II, 1991 (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 9)
  - General Electric 75th Anniversary Issue of the Schenectady Union-Star, 1953 (Oversized 1, Folder 13)
  - George, Gail, 2000; 2006; 2008; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 10)
  - George, Gail, Correspondence including Helen and Jack Script, 1997-2000 (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 11)
  - George, Gail, Correspondence, 2001-2007; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 12)
  - GE-Cartoons, Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 13)
  - Golden Anniversary Celebration, General Electric Apprentice Alumni Association Schenectady, 1963 (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 14)
  - GE Global Success, American Tragedy, Undated (Video-tape 77)
  - GE Locomotive Co, World War II, Undated (Video-tape 78)
  - GE Medicare PLUS, Undated (Video-tape 79)
  - GE Pensioners' Picket Sign, Undated (Oversized 3, Folder 3)
  - GE Pensioners Rally, 2006 April 20 (Dvd 21)
  - GE Pension Rally, 2007 April 19 (Dvd 22)
  - GE Pensions-Dennis Rocheleau, Union Relations GE, 1991; 1995; 1999-2010; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 15)
  - GE Pensions Fight '96, 1994-1996; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 16)
  - GE Pensions-Meeting, 2006 June 27 (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 17)
  - GE Pensions-Meeting, June 29, 2005 between GE and Retiree groups, Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 18)
  - GE Pension Plan and Appendices, Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 19)
  - GE Pensions, "The General Electric Pension Plan: Whose Nest Egg?", 2001-2002 (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 20)
  - GE Pensions T.V. Scripts, 1993 (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 21)
  - GE Picketing, 1994 May 19 (Video-tape 80)
  - GE Rally, 2008 April 17 (Dvd 23)
  - GE Retirees, 1994 September 24 (Video-tape 81)
  - GE Retirees, 2001 June 24 (Video-tape 82)
  - GE Retirees, 2007 March 15 (Dvd 24)
  - GE Retirees Justice Fund, 1998-2002; 2007; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 22)
  - GE Review, 1918 (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 23)
  - GE Tax Assessment and Schenectady County Citizens Fair Tax Coalition, 1992-1993 (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 24)
  - Greed Pension, Helen Quirini, 2001 April 20 (Video-tape 83)
  - Hall of Shame-Copies, 1991; 2001; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 25)
  - Hank Antonelli, 1998 May 06 (Cassette 34)
  - Hearing, Pension BM Karen, etc, 1999 September 22 (Video-tape 84)
  - Helen and Gail on Frank Duci Program, 2001 July 31 (Dvd 25)
  - Helen and Jack, 1999 (Dvd 26)
  - Helen and Jack, 1999 November 16 (Video-tape 85)
  - Helen and Jack, 1999-2001; 2008-2009; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 26)
  - Helen Quirini Notes, 1986; 1992; 2001; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 27)
  - History of GE, 1952-1954; 1978; 1991; Undated (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 28)
  - History of GE in Schenectady Scrapbook Compiled by Helen Quirini, 2001 (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 29)
  - Horizons, 1980 (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 30)
  - Immelt, Jeff, 2001-2004; 2007 (Box 3 (5-General Electric), Folder 31)
  - Info, 2004-2005 (Cd 11)
  - Information Fact Sheets about GE Pension Plans, 1969-2004; Undated (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 1)
  - "Is Mama in a Speed-Up too?": GE, UE, and Representations of Women in the Postwar Workplace, Includes Figures, 1995 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 2)
  - IUE Background, 1987; Undated (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 3)
  - IUE Memorandum, 1993; 1997-1999 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 4)
  - Jack Welch on Retirement, 2002 September 16 (Video-tape 86)
  - Job Rates at Schenectady, 1953; 1965; 1975; Undated (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 5)
  - Justice Fund, 2006 September 26 (Dvd 27)
  - Kuykendall, Mary, 1974-1975; Undated (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 6)
  - Layoffs, 1968; 1982; 1986-1987 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 7)
  - Layoffs, 1994 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 8)
  - Letters about Pensions, IUE - GE National Conference Board, Minton-Bywater, 1980; 1983; 1986-1991 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 9)
  - Letters about Pensions, IUE - GE National Conference Board, Minton-Bywater, 1992-1997 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 10)
  - Letters from Immelt, 2007 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 11)
  - Letters from Welch, 1982-2001 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 12)
  - Letters to Jeff Immelt from Others, 2001-2002; 2007; Undated (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 13)
  - Letters to the Editor by Helen Quirini, 1985-2007; Undated (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 14)
  - Letters to the Editor by Others, 1987; 1991-1995; 1998-2000; 2007; Undated (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 15)
  - Letters to Welch from Others, 1984-2002; Undated (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 16)
  - Local 301 Retirees Communication and Outreach about Pensions, 1987-2010; Undated (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 17)
  - Lucy and Jim Conley, Undated (Cassette 36)
  - Medicaid Seminar, Undated (Cassette 37)
  - Memorandum of Settlement between General Electronic Company and IUE, 2003 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 18)
  - Miller, Edna Bailey, 1965-2003; Undated (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 19-20)
  - Minutes from Meeting with Division Heads, Undated (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 21)
  - Mo-Gen Message, 1976; 1978 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 22)
  - My Letters to Immelt, 2005-2006 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 23)
  - My Letters to Welch, 1985-1986; 1988; 1990-1991; 1993; Undated (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 24)
  - Motor Mirror, 1955-1957 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 25)
  - M's Ds, Performance Art, Undated (Video-tape 87)
  - Negotiations, 1991 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 26)
  - Negotiations, 1994 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 27)
  - Negotiations, 1995 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 28)
  - Negotiations, 1997 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 29)
  - Negotiations, 2000-2001 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 30)
  - Negotiations, 2003 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 31)
  - Negotiations, 2007 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 32)
  - News at Large, 1972-1973 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 33)
  - News Clippings about GE Retirees and Pensions, 1946-1953; 1968 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 34)
  - News Clippings about GE Retirees and Pensions, 1973-1974; 1980; 1983-1989 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 35)
  - News Clippings about GE Retirees and Pensions, 1990-1999 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 36)
  - News Clippings about GE Retirees and Pensions, 2000-2003 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 37)
  - News Clippings about GE Retirees and Pensions, 2005-2009; Undated (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 38)
  - News Notes for Pensioner, 1998 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 39)
  - On the Line with Mac Motors, 1970 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 40)
  - Oral History Association Meeting, GE Project, Cleveland, Ohio, 1992 October 16 (Cassette 35)
  - Packet for Retirees during Negotiations with Co. and Union, 1997 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 41)
  - Panoramic Photographs of Picketing at GE, 2003 (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 42)
  - Panoramic Photographs of Retirees and Workers at Local 301, Undated (Box 4 (5-General Electric), Folder 43)
  - Panoramic Photographs of Retiree Rally at GE Annual Meeting in North Carolina, 2003 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 1)
  - Pay Stubs, 1955-1957 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 2)
  - Pay Stubs, 1958-1959 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 3)
  - Pay Stubs, 1960-1961 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 4)
  - Pay Stubs, 1962-1963 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 5)
  - Pay Stubs, 1964; 1966-1967; 1969-1975 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 6)
  - Pay Stubs, 1976-1977; 1979-1980; Undated (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 7)
  - Pay Vouchers, 1945-1946 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 8)
  - Pension, Age Discrimination Case, 2008 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 9)
  - "Pension Fund Story: Workers Pay, GE Benefits", 2003; Undated (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 10)
  - Pension Materials Before Helen Qurini's Retirement, 1954; 1956; 1973-1978; Undated (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 11)
  - Pension Plan, 2003 (Cd 12)
  - Pension Rights Center, 1986-1995; 2000-2001; 2005-2009; Undated (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 12)
  - Pensions, GE, Undated (Dvd 28)
  - Pension Speeches by Helen Quirini Not Delivered at GE Annual Meetings, 1997; Undated (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 13)
  - Pension Trust, 1993; 2001; 2003 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 14)
  - Petitions, 1989; 1991-1992; Undated (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 15)
  - Photographs of Retirees, 1984; 1986-1989 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 16)
  - Photographs of Retirees, 1992; 1994-1996 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 17)
  - Photographs of Retirees, 1997-1999 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 18)
  - Photographs of Retirees, 2001 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 19)
  - Photographs of Retirees, 2000-2001; 2003-2004 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 20)
  - Photographs of Retirees, 2005 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 21)
  - Photographs of Retirees, 2006-2008 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 22)
  - Photographs of Retirees at Christmas, 2004; 2006 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 23)
  - Photographs of Retirees Picketing, 1998 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 24)
  - Photographs of Retirees Picketing, 2003 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 25)
  - Photographs of Retirees Picketing, Undated (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 26-28)
  - Poster Display of GE Retirees Picketing in Schenectady, 2003-2006 (Flat-file 1)
  - Publications, Manufacturing Processes, 1955; 1958; 1974; Undated (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 29)
  - Rallies, Undated (Cd 13)
  - Quarter Century Club, 1919-1924 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 30)
  - Quarter Century Club, 1926; 1945; 1964 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 31)
  - Quirini, GE Speech, 301 Pensions, Undated (Video-tape 88)
  - Raise, 1985; 1987-1988; 1991; Undated (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 32)
  - Raise, 2000 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 33)
  - Rally at Schenectady GE, 2002 April 18 (Video-tape 89)
  - Rally at Schenectady GE, 2003 April 17 (Video-tape 90)
  - Rally for GE Retirees, Justice Fund, 1999 (Video-tape 91)
  - Ralph Boyd, 1999 July 20 (Cassette 38-39)
  - Reagan, 1982-1983; 1986-1987; 1989; 2004 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 34)
  - Reproduced Images from General Electric Foundry from 1925, Undated (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 35)
  - Retiree Meeting, 2007 March 15 (Dvd 29)
  - Retiree News, 1987-1994; Undated (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 36)
  - Retirees Column Local 301 News, Written by Helen Quirini, 2001-2002 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 37)
  - Retirees Meeting, 2008 May 18 (Dvd 30)
  - Retirees Rally, 1991 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 38)
  - Retirees Rally, 1992 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 39)
  - Retirees Rally, 1995 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 40)
  - Retirees Rally, 1996 (Box 5 (5-General Electric), Folder 41)
  - Retirees Rally, 2000 (Video-tape 92)
  - Retirees Rally, 2001 (Video-tape 93)
  - Retirees Rally, 2001 April 10 (Video-tape 96)
  - Retirees Rally-INF, 2000-2001; Undated (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 1)
  - Retirees Rally, Justice Fund, 1998 June 18 (Video-tape 94)
  - Retirees Rally, Meeting and Negotiations, 1990 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 2)
  - Retirees Rally, Schenectady, 2001 April 19 (Video-tape 95)
  - Retirement Party, Edna Miller, 1975 September 13 (Cassette 40)
  - Rules for Lift Truck Operation and Hyster's Lift Truck Operator's Manuel, 1970; 1975 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 3)
  - Safety Manual, 1943 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 4)
  - Schenectady Business News, 1987 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 5)
  - Schenectady Business News, 1988 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 6)
  - Schenectady Business News, 1989 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 7)
  - Schenectady Business News, 1990 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 8)
  - Schenectady Business News, 1991 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 9)
  - Schenectady Business News, 1993-1997 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 10)
  - Schenectady Business News, 1998-2000 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 11)
  - Schenectady Has Guts, Undated (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 12)
  - Scrapbook, Local 301 Retirees Pension Fund Activities Created by Helen Quirini, ca. 1997 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 13)
  - Spotlight, 1971-1972 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 14)
  - Spotlight, 1973-1974 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 15)
  - Spotlight, 1975-1976 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 16)
  - Stories of Women Significant in Our Lives Produced and Directed by Gail George, Undated (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 17)
  - Suggestions from Helen Quirini, 1942-1945 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 18-19)
  - Suggestions from Helen Quirini, 1947-1969 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 20-21)
  - Suggestions from Helen Quirini, 1974 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 22)
  - Survey of GE Retirees-[RESTRICTED], 1993 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 23)
  - Time Standards, 1954 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 24)
  - T-Shirts, Including Ones About General Electric Retirees, Undated (Oversized 8)
  - War Production Council, 1944 March 28 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 25)
  - Work Practices and Employees Manuals, 1926; 1972; Undated (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 26)
  - War Loan and Blood Drives, 1944; Undated (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 27)
  - Welch, Jack, 1985-1988; 1991-2009; Undated (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 28-31)
  - Wizards of Schenectady, Dr. C. Guy Saints and his Flying Machine, 2007 (Dvd 31)
  - Wizards of Schenectady, C. Guy Saints, 2008 January 01 (Dvd 32)
  - Working at GE, 2005 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 32)
  - World War II Activities at General Electric in Candid Camera, 1944 (Oversized 1, Folder 14)
  - WRGB Community Leader Ascertainment Meeting, 1994 (Box 6 (5-General Electric), Folder 33)
- Community Activism, 1898-2010; Undated; 6
  Arranged alphabetically within each subseries.
  This series includes records collected and created by Helen Quirini that document her involvement in numerous issues and community organizations. The material in this series is divided into eight subseries and includes meeting minutes, agendas, financial information, news clippings, reports, correspondence, newsletters and other publications, notes, pamphlets, brochures, conference materials, fact sheets and photographs.
  - Human Rights, 1967-2005; Undated; 6.1; 3.19 cubic ft.
    Arranged alphabetically
    This subseries documents Schenectady County's Human Rights Committee and its day-to-day activities, as well as learning materials developed by the group for the community. The subseries contains agendas, annual reports, minutes, news clippings, magazines, pamphlets and booklets. It features materials on the Martin Luther King Jr. Commemoration, the March 19th Coalition and information on other coalitions that combated racism. Included in this subseries are the 1972 Mont Pleasant High School hearings, during which Helen Quirini questioned students at her alma mater about escalating racial tension.
    - Affirmative Action, 1980 September 24 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 1)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1968; 1971-1974 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 2)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1975 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 3)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1976 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 4)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1977 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 5)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1978 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 6)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1979 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 7)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1980 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 8)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1981 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 9)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1982 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 10)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1983 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 11)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1984 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 12)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1985 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 13)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1986 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 14)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1987 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 15)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1988 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 16-17)
    - Agendas, Minutes, and Supplemental Materials, 1989-1990 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 18)
    - Annual Reports, 1970-1972; 1975-1977 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 19)
    - Annual Reposrts and Budget, 1979-1980 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 20)
    - Annual Reports, 1981; 1984; 1986 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 21)
    - Articles and Clippings, 1967-1991 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 22)
    - Banner Commemorating March on Washington, 1963 (Oversized 17)
    - "Black History Month: Toward a Global Perspective in Education", 1984 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 23)
    - The Capital District Coalition of Conscience: A Dedication to Martin Luther King and Supplemental Material, 1979-1990 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 24)
    - "Children in Need: Investment Strategies for the Educationally Disadvantaged," Pamphlet, 1987 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 25)
    - Civil Rights: A National, Not a Special Interest, 1981 June 25 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 26)
    - Church of the Creator, Schenectady, "Jews Rule America" and "Declaration of Independence from Jewish Tyranny,", 1983 May 09 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 27)
    - Committee to Combat Racism and Anti-Semitism (1 of 2), 1982-1984 (Box 1 (6-Community Activism), Folder 28)
    - Committee to Combat Racism and Anti-Semitism (2 of 2), 1982-1984 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 1)
    - Concerned for the Hungry-Flyer and Pamphlets, Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 2)
    - Coping with Vandalism: Task Force Report to the Board of the Education, 1977 March (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 3)
    - "The Dialogue Journal", 1967 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 4)
    - Dissemination of Policy, Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 5)
    - Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 1986 May 31 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 6)
    - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1981-1982 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 7)
    - Executive Director Expectations, Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 8)
    - Father Girzone, 1973; 1979; 1990-2005 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 9)
    - Father Girzone, 1994 (Video-tape 97)
    - "Fifth Amendment Today", 1965 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 10)
    - Friendship Baptist Church Hearing, Correspondence and Clippings, 1982; 1984 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 11)
    - "From Jumpstreet", 1982 December 17; 1983 Janaury 12 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 12)
    - Giardina, James-Clippings, Obituary, 1976 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 13)
    - Hamilton Hill Forum, 2002 March 01 (Video-tape 98)
    - Handwritten Notes, Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 14)
    - Housing-Correspondence and Article, 1970; 1971 February 12 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 15)
    - "Ideas on Poverty and Welfare"- Helen Qurini, Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 16)
    - Ku Klux Klan, 1980-1981 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 17)
    - Law, Order and Justice Center, 1982 Fall; Undated (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 18)
    - "A Layman's View of the Functioning of Law, Order, and Justice in Schenectady", 1971 Summer (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 19)
    - "A Lover's Quarrel with my Native Land", 1967 March 12 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 20)
    - Magazines in Regard to Martin Luther King, 1968; 1969 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 21)
    - March 19th Coalition, 1992-1998 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 22-23)
    - March on Washington Committee, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 24)
    - March on Washington Program, 1963 August 28 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 25)
    - Martin Luther King Jr. Commemoration, 1980-1992 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 26-28)
    - Martin Luther King Jr. Commemoration-Pamphlets and Programs, 1976-1991 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 29)
    - Mont Pleasant High School, 1969; 1972-1973 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 30-32)
    - Mont Pleasant High School Hearings, 1972 February 29-1972 March 01 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 33-36)
    - NAACP, 1995-2002 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 37-38)
    - National Symposium of Nonviolence, 1989 November 09-1989 November 11 (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 39)
    - New York Teachers and IUE Newsletters, 1982 January 10; 1989 January (Box 2 (6-Community Activism), Folder 40)
    - News Coverage of the March on Washington and the Assassination of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., 1963; 1968-1969 (Oversized 3, Folder 4)
    - Newsletter and Supplement, 1972; 1974 January-1974 February; 1982-1986 (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 1)
    - Outreach Listening Team and Listening Circles, 1983; Undated (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 2)
    - Our Black Prisons, 1981 July (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 3)
    - Pamphlets, 1962-1981; Undated (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 4)
    - Poverty and Public Policy Conference, 1996 (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 5)
    - Prison Alternatives, 1981 (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 6)
    - Probation Project, Undated (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 7)
    - Report on Schenectady County Jail, 1971-1972 (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 8)
    - Schenectady City School District, Equal Employment and Educational Opportunities Committee, 1982; 1985; Undated (Box 3 (6-Community Activism), Folder 9)